We are going to talk today about the sequel of "Inconvenient Truth."
سنتحدث اليوم حول تكملة للحقيقة المزعجة.
It's time again to talk about "Inconvenient Truth,"
أنه الوقت مجدداً للحديث عن الحقيقة المزعجة،
a truth that everyone is concerned about,
الحقيقة التي يهتم بها الجميع،
but nobody is willing to talk about.
لكن لا يرغب أي أحد في الحديث عنها.
Somebody has to take the lead, and I decided to do it.
ويجب أن يبادر أحد ما، وقد قررت أن أفعل ذلك.
If you are scared by global warming,
اذا كنت تخاف من إرتفاع الحرارة العالمية،
wait until we learn about local warming.
أنتظر حتى تتعلم شيئاً عن إرتفاع الحرارة المحلية.
We will talk today about local warming.
سنتحدث اليوم عن إرتفاع الحرارة المحلية.
Important health message: blogging may be hazardous to your health,
رسالة صحية مهمة: التدوين قد يكون خطرا على صحتك،
especially if you are a male.
خصوصاً إذا انت مُذكر.
This message is given as a public service.
هذه الرسالة قُدمت باعتبارها خدمة عامة.
Blogging affects your posture. We start with the posture.
يؤثر التدوين على حالتك. نبدأ بهذه الحالة.
This is the posture of ladies who are not blogging;
هذه وضعية السيدات اللائي لا يدونون.
this is the posture of ladies who are blogging.
وهذه وضعية السيدات اللائي يدونون.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
This is the natural posture of a man sitting,
هذه وضع طبيعي لرجل يجلس،
squatting for ventilation purposes.
القرفصاء لأغراض التهوية.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And this is the natural posture of a standing man,
وهذه وضعية طبيعية لرجل واقف.
and I think this picture inspired Chris to insert me
وأعتقد أن هذه الصورة ألهمت كريس ليضعني
into the lateral thinking session.
في جلسة التفكير الحرفي.
This is male blogging posture sitting, and the result is,
هذه وضع رجل مدوّن يجلس، والنتيجة هي،
"For greater comfort,
"من أجل راحة أفضل،
men naturally sit with their legs farther apart than women,
يجلس الرجال طبيعياً مع أرجلهم بعيدة عن بعضها خلافاً للسيدات،
when working on laptop.
عند الإنشغال بالحاسوب المحمول.
However, they will adopt a less natural posture
بينما، يتخذون أوضاع أقل طبيعيةً
in order to balance it on their laps,
من أجل موازنته علي ارجلهم،
which resulted in a significant rise of body heat
التي أدت إلي زيادة ملحوظة لحرارة الجسم
between their thighs." This is the issue of local warming.
بين أفخاذهم." هذه هي قضية إرتفاع الحرارة المحلية.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
This is a very serious newspaper; it's Times of England --
هذه صحيفة جادة جداً، أنها صحيفة التايمز الإنجليزية--
very serious. This is a very --
جادة جداً. هذا --
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
-- gentlemen and ladies, be serious.
-- السادة والسيدات، كونوا جادين.
This is a very serious research, that you should read the underline.
هذا بحث جاد جداً، يتوجب عليك قرأة ما تحته خط.
And be careful, your genes are in danger.
وكن حذراً، جيناتك في خطر.
Will geeks become endangered species?
هل سيصبح المهوسون مخلوقات مهددة بالإنقراض؟
The fact: population growth in countries with high laptop --
الحقيقة: النمو السكاني في البلاد ذات الحواسيب المحمولة الأكثر--
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I need Hans Rosling to give me a graph.
أريد أن يعطيني هانس روزلين رسماً بيانياً.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Global warming fun.
مرح الدفء العالمي.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But let's keep things in proportion.
لكن دعونا نحافظ على الأمور في تناسب.
How to take care in five easy steps:
كيف تعتني بهذا في خمسة خطوات سهلة.
first of all, you can use natural ventilation. You can use body breath.
أولاً، يمكنك إستخدام التهوية الطبيعية. يمكنك إستخدام التنفس بالجسد.
You should stay cool with the appropriate clothing.
يجب أن تحافظ على الهدوء مع الملابس المناسبة.
You should care about your posture -- this is not right.
يجب أن تعتني بحالتك-- هذا ليس صحيحاً.
Can you extract from Chris another minute and a half for me,
هل يمكنك إستخلاص دقيقة ونصف من كريس من أجلي،
because I have a video I have to show you.
لأن لدي فيديو ويجب أن أعرضه عليكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
You are great. This is the correct posture.
أنك عظيم. هذه هي الحالة الصحيحة.
Another benefit of Wi-Fi, we learned yesterday about the benefits of Wi-Fi.
فائدة أخرى للشبكات اللاسلكية، تعلمنا البارحة حول فوائد الشبكات اللاسلكية.
Wi-Fi enables you to avoid the processor. And there are some enhanced
تتيح لنا الشبكات اللاسلكية تجنب المعالجات. وهناك بعض التحسينات
protection measures, which I would like to share with you,
في معايير الحماية التي أريد أن أتقاسمها معكم،
and I would like, in a minute, to thank Philips for helping.
وأريد، في دقيقة، أن أشكر فيليبس علي المساعدة.
This is a research which was done in '86, but it's still valid.
هذا بحث نُشر عام 1986، لكنه ما يزال صحيحاً.
Scrotal temperature reflects intratesticular temperature
درجة حرارة الصفن تعكس درجة حرارة الخصية
and is lowered by shaving.
ويمكن تخيفضها بالحلاقة.
By the way, I must admit, my English is not so good,
بالمناسبة، يجب أن أعترف، أن لغتي الإنجليزية ليست جيدة،
I didn't know what is scrotal; I understand it's a scrotum.
لم أعرف ما هو الصفن. لقد فهمته كيس الصفن.
I guess in plural it's scrotal, like medium and media.
أخمن أن الجمع هو الصفن، مثل الوسط والإعلام.
Digital scrotum, digital media.
الصفن الرقمي، الإعلام الرقمي.
And only last year I recognized that I'm a proud scrotum owner.
وفقط العام الماضي عرفت أنني مالك صفن فخور.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And this research is being precipitated by the U.S. government,
وهذا البحث عجلته الحكومة الأمريكية،
so you can see that your tax man is working for good causes.
لذا يمكنكم رؤية رجل الضرائب يعمل لأهداف طيبة.
Video: Man: The Philips Bodygroom has a sleek,
فيديو: رجل: هذا فيليبس في بودي قروم الأنيق،
ergonomic design for a safe and easy way to trim
تصميم مريح لوضع آمن وسهل للحلاقة
those scruffy underarm hairs, the untidy curls on and around your
ذلك الشعر الوضيع تحت الإبط، والشعر المجعد الذي لا يليق بك
[bleep], as well as the hard to reach locks on the underside of your
(صافرة)، وكذلك الأماكن التي يصعب الوصول اليها ألى ألاسفل من
[bleep] and [bleep]. Once you use the Bodygroom, the world looks different.
(صافرة)، (صافرة). بمجرد إستخدامك لبودي قروم، يبدو العالم مختلفاً.
And so does your [bleep]. These days, with a hair-free back,
وايضاً (صافرة). هذه الأيام، مع ظهر خالي من الشعر،
well-groomed shoulders and an extra optical inch on my [bleep],
الأكتاف المهندمة والبوصة الضوئية الإضافية في (صافرة)،
well, let's just say life has gotten pretty darn cozy.
حسناً، دعنا نقول أن الحياة صارت دافئة بقوة.
Yossi Vardi: This is one of the most popular viral advertisement of last year,
يوشي فاردي: كان هذا أحد الإعلانات شعبيةً في العام الماضي،
known as the optical inch by Philips. Let's applaud Philips --
معروف بالبوصة الضوئية بطولة فيليبس. لنصفق لفيلبس--
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
-- for this gesture for humanity.
-- لهذه اللفتة للبشرية.
And this is how they are promoting the product. This is --
وهكذا يروجون للمنتج. هذا هو--
I didn't touch it, this is original.
لم ألمسه، هذا أصلي.
Laptop use to solve overpopulation. And if everything failed,
يُستخدم الحاسوب المحمول لحل مشكلة إزدياد السكان. واذا فشل أي شئ،
there are some secondary uses.
هناك بعض الإستخدامات الثانوية.
And then our next talk, our next TED if you invite me
وبعد ذلك في مؤتمر تيد القادم، اذا قمتم بدعوتي
will be why you should not carry a cell phone in your pocket.
سيكون حول لماذا لا يجب علينا وضع هواتفنا المحمولة في جيوبنا.
And this is what the young generation says.
وهذا ما يقوله الشباب من الأجيال الحديثة.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
And I just want to show you that I'm not just preaching,
واردت فقط أن أظهر لكم أنني لا أوعظ فقط،
but I also practice.
لكنني أيضاً أطبق.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
4 am in the morning.
الساعة الرابعة فجراً.
You cannot use this picture.
لا يمكنكم إستخدام هذه الصورة.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Now, I have some mini TED Prizes, this is the Philips Bodygroom,
الآن، لدي بعض الهدايا الصغيرة لتيد، هذا هو بودي قروم لفيليب،
one for our leader.
واحدة لقائدنا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Anybody feels threatened, anybody really need it?
أي شخص آخر يحس التهديد، أي شخص يحتاجها فعلاً؟
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Any lady, any lady? Thank you very much.
أي سيدة، أي سيدة؟ شكراً جزيلاً لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)